<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on Hugo Whisper Theme</title>
    <link>/course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on Hugo Whisper Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>/course/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/syllabus/</guid>
      <description> The four-week summer component of aims to guide students through the processing of designing experiments and analyzing commonly used for data for disaster response. Daily course material, case studies, guest lectures, and small-group projects will expose students to challenges across technical domains. This syallabus is subject to change over the duration of the course.
Schedule Week 1: Foundation  Introduction to Remote Sensing for Humanitarian Assistance and Disaster Relief Review of online Python course GIS and networks in Python Field trip to MIT Lincoln Laboratory  Week 2: Data Science and Analysis  Introduction to engineering design and data science principles Images, metadata, and image processing Field trip to Massachusetts Task Force One (MA-TF1)  Week 3: Aerial Imagery and Sensing  Civil Air Patrol and Aerial Imagery Internet of things and analyzing aerial images Building a hardware multispectral sensor Kite photography Field trip to Draper Laboratory  Week 4: Optimization Decision Making  Network optimization and class optimization formulations Guest lectures from Swissnex and Red Cross Red Crescent Climate Centre Final exercise of disaster tabletop simulation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Trips</title>
      <link>/course/field-trips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/field-trips/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the Remote Sensing course, students embark on field trips to learn more about crisis response and about possible applications of their coursework. The following represents the field trips completed during the 2019 Remote Sensing program. The specific field trips done by each class may vary in future years.
MIT Lincoln Laboratory MIT Lincoln Laboratory (MIT-LL), a co-sponsor for the Beaver Works Summer Institute. The Laboratory focuses on research that improves national security and assists in humanitarian aid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>/course/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/python/</guid>
      <description> Python 00-InitialSetup
01-Intro-to-python 02-visualization-and-shapes
 How to use Jupyter/Colab Notebooks Install system packages with apt, and python packages with pip Fundamentals of python and programming:  packages loops and conditionals functions data structures: lists, dictionaries, iterators  Numpy  Arrays Indexing Matrix math summary functions (max, min, std, avg)  Pandas  column names, data types filtering and logical indexing joining, pivoting generating statistics  Visualizing data  matplotlib, histograms, heatmaps, imshow time series, graphs   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS and Networks</title>
      <link>/course/gis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/gis/</guid>
      <description>GIS and Networks 03-Intro-to-GIS
04-Intro-to-networks
05-Intro-to-Data-Science
 Engineering design and data science  How is data used to make decisions? How to identify requirements, constraints, and problems? How to effectively communicate between teams? How can engineering projects fail? What causes failures? How do we learn from failures? How to store and access data in a database for analysis?  Geographic information system (GIS)  How to use GeoPandas How to load various GIS file formats How to load raster files with GDAL How to create a map with layers How to do spatial calculations  Common GIS tasks  Loading basemaps from repositories Loading shapefiles of data layers Geometric operations for overlays, intersection, union, etc Reclassifying data Loading raster files Computing nearest neighbors, distances, spatial averages, spatial join Machine Learning and forecast-based financing  Networks  What are networks and how to use them How to get network data from Open Street Maps?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplements</title>
      <link>/course/supplements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/supplements/</guid>
      <description> Supplements  What are some classical engineering failures? What went wrong? What is uncertainty? How can we model and characterize uncertainty? What is classification? What are some techniques for classification (decision trees, K-NN)? What is regression? What are some techniques for regression (linear, kernel)? What is uncertainity? How do we characterize it (bootstrap, random forest, Gaussian models)? History of image recognition  Imagenet large scale visual recognition challenge Convolutional neural networks image labeling tasks existing datasets  Labeling images  Types of annotation: scene, point, polygon Need for labels/data set for HADR Manually labeling data  Pretrained image labelers  Open source implementations Commercial implementations Transfer learning Using labels in decision making   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Processing</title>
      <link>/course/image-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/image-processing/</guid>
      <description>Aerial Photography and Image Processing 06-Intro-to-Image-processing
07-Satellite_Image_Processing_Using_Python
 What is the Civil Air Patrol (CAP)?  History and mission of CAP What information does aerial imagery provide? What challenges are there in dealing with aerial imagery? What goes into planning CAP missions? Elevation, distance, path, targets  What kind of information is available from satellite imagery, and how is it used?  Sources of public imagery Sensing bands Preprocessing, Calibration Analyses, uses, limitation  Imagery data  How are images represented on a computer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optics</title>
      <link>/course/optics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/optics/</guid>
      <description>Kite Flying and Optics  Kite photograpy  What are the operational and safety considerations? Payload size, weight, and power (SWaP) Best practices for launching a kite  Optics and spectral nature of light  Light, energy, photons, Blackbody radiation Spectrum of light Absorption, Reflectivity Camera sensors, channels Multispectral sensing  Converting a webcam into near-field IR camera Raspberry Pi  How to connect to Raspberry Pi Loading programs Connecting a webcam Taking images with the webcam and saving  Visualizing and analyzing multispectral images  Using openCV to analyze each channel Compute photosynthesis levels with NDVI Accounting for white balance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization</title>
      <link>/course/optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/optimization/</guid>
      <description>Decision Making and Optimization  Decision making  What decisions need to be made in HADR applications? Who makes those decisions? What information is necessary to support decisions? What costs/benefits/constraints are considered? What is optimization? What kind of optimization problems are there? How to sort data?  What optimization problems can be done on graphs?  What is optimization? Why is optimization difficult? Combinatorial difficulty, integer problems What kinds of optimization problems are there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specimen</title>
      <link>/course/specimen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/course/specimen/</guid>
      <description>Markdown Test Page  Headings Paragraphs Blockquotes Lists Horizontal rule Table Code Inline elements  Headings Heading one Sint sit cillum pariatur eiusmod nulla pariatur ipsum. Sit laborum anim qui mollit tempor pariatur nisi minim dolor. Aliquip et adipisicing sit sit fugiat commodo id sunt. Nostrud enim ad commodo incididunt cupidatat in ullamco ullamco Lorem cupidatat velit enim et Lorem.
Heading two Aute officia nulla deserunt do deserunt cillum velit magna.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>